<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="schema/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--OLD FILENAME:letters_659.xml-->
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="HENSLOW-659">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
            <title xml:id="main_title">From H. J. H. Bond   24 October 1860</title>
        </titleStmt>
        <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Henslow Correspondence Project</authority>
            <publisher>Henslow Correspondence Project</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
            <availability status="restricted">
                <p>Available under license only</p>
            </availability>
            <availability xml:id="displayImageRights" status="restricted">
                <p>Zooming image © Cambridge University Library, All rights reserved.</p>
            </availability>
            <availability xml:id="downloadImageRights" status="restricted">
                <licence>This image may be used in accord with fair use and fair dealing provisions, including teaching and research. If you wish to reproduce it within publications or on the public web, please make a reproduction request.</licence>
            </availability>
            <availability xml:id="metadataRights" status="restricted">
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This metadata is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International (CC BY-NC 4.0).</licence>
            </availability>

        </publicationStmt>

        <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
                <msIdentifier>
                    <repository>Cambridge University Library</repository>
                    <idno>MS Add. 8177: 32</idno>
                </msIdentifier>
                <msContents>
                    <msItem>
                        <title copyOf="#main_title"/>
                    </msItem>
                </msContents>
            </msDesc>
        </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
        <correspDesc>
            <correspAction type="sent">
                <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_247.xml">Bond, H. J. H.</persName>
                <date when="1860-10-24">24 October 1860</date>
            </correspAction>
            <correspAction type="received">
                <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_1.xml">Henslow, J. S.</persName>
            </correspAction>
        </correspDesc>
        <abstract>
            <p>Discusses JSH’s attendance at Cambridge University medical examinations, for students who need to be examined in botany as well. Need for attendance uncertain.</p>
        </abstract>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
        <change when="2014-06-06">Converted to XML by <name xml:id="hjones">Huw Jones</name>
         </change>
        <change when="2016-05-17">Converted to TEI P5 by <name xml:id="mjhawkins">Michael Hawkins</name>
         </change>
        <change when="2020-08-10" type="letter" status="released">Transcription cleared for online release</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
      <body>
        <div type="letter">
            <div type="text">
                <opener>
                    <placeName>Cambridge</placeName>
                    <date>24 October 1860</date>
                    <salute>Dear Henslow</salute>
                </opener>
                <div type="transcription">
                     
                  <p>I cannot at present tell you for certain whether there will be any candidates to be examined in Botany for this M.B. Examination this term, as they are not obliged to send notice of their intention of offering themselves till the Monday previous to the Examination and the only candidate that I have at present received a notice from, is exempted from examination in Botany from having distinguished himself in that Science Tripos in that subject— Still I think there will be one or two to be so examined— When I can, I will give you further information on the matter—</p>
                  <p>With respect to Examiners not being expected to be present to examine, I really can give no opinion beyond that that the Board of Med. Studies have generally thought it to be inexpedient—Prof <hi rend="superscript">r</hi> Cumming, however, in consequence of his greatly advanced age will scarcely I imagine be present—</p>
                  <p>There is this difficulty however: it sometimes happens that candidates offer themselves for both examinations for the M.B. degree, but till the result of the 1 <hi rend="superscript">st</hi> Exam is known they cannot proceed to the 2 <hi rend="superscript">nd</hi>, consequently the delay in ascertaining the result from an absentee Examiner might be found very inconvenient—</p>
                  <p>Believe me | yours very truly |H J H Bond</p> 
                </div>
            </div>

        </div>
        
      </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
