<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="schema/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="HENSLOW-1086">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="main_title">To Thomas Martin 28 January 1850</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Henslow Correspondence Project</authority>
                <publisher>Henslow Correspondence Project</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
                <availability status="restricted">
                    <p>Available under license only</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="displayImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <p>Zooming image © Cambridge University Library, All rights reserved.</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="downloadImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <licence>This image may be used in accord with fair use and fair dealing
                        provisions, including teaching and research. If you wish to reproduce it
                        within publications or on the public web, please make a reproduction
                        request.</licence>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="metadataRights" status="restricted">
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This metadata is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International (CC BY-NC 4.0).</licence>
            </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>Bury St Edmunds Public Record Office</repository>
                        <collection/>
                        <idno>FL586/13/1: 33</idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <msItem>
                            <title copyOf="#main_title"/>
                        </msItem>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sent">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_1.xml">Henslow, J. S.</persName>
                    <date when="1850-01-28">28 January 1850</date>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="received">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_368.xml">Martin, Thomas</persName>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2014-06-06">Converted to XML by <name xml:id="hjones">Huw
                Jones</name>
         </change>
            <change when="2016-05-17">Converted to TEI P5 by <name xml:id="mjhawkins">Michael
                    Hawkins</name>
         </change>
        <change when="2020-08-10" type="letter" status="released">Transcription cleared for online release</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="letter">
                <div type="text">
                    <opener>
                        <placeName>Hitcham Hadleigh Suffolk</placeName>
                        <date>28 January 1850</date>
                        <salute>My dear Sir,</salute>
                    </opener>
                    <div type="transcription">
                        <p>Thanks for the papers which I shall circulate with the Cottage Gardener,
                            pasted on cover – I have not seen any more of the Morn. Chronicle’s
                            statements than a few extracts in the Bury Post having reference to
                            Suffolk – I have learnt to be very suspicious of Reporters’ statements –
                            They contrive to dress up a few facts, sufficiently lamentable in
                            themselves, in colors not warranted by a closer examination of details –
                            I was told by a friend at Stourmouth that the details from that
                            neighbourhood were very unfair representations of the state of things –
                            Certainly I could not agree with the apparent approval of a system
                            adopted by a friend of mine in a neighboring parish ­ who builds model
                            cottages, – then covenants with the tenants that they shall not keep on
                            pigs or fowls – out of respect to Farmers’ prejudices – It seems true to
                            me that Farmers’ prejudices are of all things that men have to contend
                            with, the most injurious to the welfare of the Labourer – It requires
                            long residence in a Country village &amp; close acquaintance with the
                            people to be able to enter into the feelings &amp; prejudices peculiar
                            to our agricultural districts – &amp; I am sure no hasty visits of a
                            newspaper reporter can qualify him for making a correct statement – I
                            had made enquiry after these articles but had not been able to get sight
                            of them – If they are ever published apart I will get them – As yet we
                            have had fewer persons in the Workhouse than by this time last year –
                            the cheapness of provisions more than compensating for any loss of
                            labour–</p>
                        <p>Ever yrs truly</p>
                        <p>J. S. Henslow</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
