<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="schema/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="HENSLOW-1127">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="main_title">To Unknown July 1859</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Henslow Correspondence Project</authority>
                <publisher>Henslow Correspondence Project</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
                <availability status="restricted">
                    <p>Available under license only</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="displayImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <p>Zooming image © Cambridge University Library, All rights reserved.</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="downloadImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <licence>This image may be used in accord with fair use and fair dealing
                        provisions, including teaching and research. If you wish to reproduce it
                        within publications or on the public web, please make a reproduction
                        request.</licence>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="metadataRights" status="restricted">
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This metadata is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International (CC BY-NC 4.0).</licence>
            </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>American Philosophical Society</repository>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <msItem>
                            <title copyOf="#main_title"/>
                        </msItem>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sent">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_1.xml">Henslow, J. S.</persName>
                    <date notBefore="1859-07-01" notAfter="1859-07-31">July 1859</date>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="received">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_289.xml">Unknown</persName>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2014-06-06">Converted to XML by <name xml:id="hjones">Huw
                Jones</name>
         </change>
            <change when="2016-05-17">Converted to TEI P5 by <name xml:id="mjhawkins">Michael
                    Hawkins</name>
         </change>
        <change when="2020-08-10" type="letter" status="released">Transcription cleared for online release</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="letter">
                <div type="text">
                    <opener>
                        <placeName>Hitcham Bildeston Suffolk</placeName>
                        <date>July 1859</date>
                        <salute>My dear Sir,</salute>
                    </opener>
                    <div type="transcription">
                        <p>Will you be so good as to correct an omission in the Hitcham List. Above chenopodianths should be inserted</p>
                        <p>Sect. 4. Incomplete</p>
                        <p>which escaped notice in looking over the proof.</p>
                        <p>Bentham expressly intended his book for beginners, &amp; others who are not likely to become profound in Botany. I have become so thoroughly satisfied of the great advantage of introducing Botany into Village School - that I devote every Monday to the subject - &amp; I think if you were some day to favour me with a visit you would see at once how useful it can be made. I will send by this post a document or two which will show you the manner in which attempt to <hi rend="underline">work it</hi> in with other subjects. On Tuesday (if fine) all hands (about 3 doz. volunteers) will turn into our wood, &amp; thoroughly search it. If every Village in England had a battery of sharp eyes what an accumulation to be digested for the Cybele! You would find it difficult to puzzle my chief pupil Teacher in regard to the name &amp; classification of a Hitcham species - &amp; she would tell you the Order of most of our common garden plants - in to the bargain. It is in School work that I expect Bentham's book will ultimately prove most useful. But when shall we have School work in Botany?</p>
                        <p>We had a famous day for our Hort. Show on Wednesday. The produce better than I ever saw it before. It has been continually improving. Nearly 300 of the peasants sat down to tea &amp; more peaceable &amp; well behaved set it is hardly possible to meet with.</p>
                        <p>Yrs very truly</p>
                        <p>J. S. Henslow</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
