<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="schema/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--OLD FILENAME:letters_100.xml-->
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="HENSLOW-100">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
            <title xml:id="main_title">From R. T. Lowe   27 November 1829</title>
        </titleStmt>
        <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Henslow Correspondence Project</authority>
            <publisher>Henslow Correspondence Project</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
            <availability status="restricted">
                <p>Available under license only</p>
            </availability>
            <availability xml:id="displayImageRights" status="restricted">
                <p>Zooming image © Cambridge University Library, All rights reserved.</p>
            </availability>
            <availability xml:id="downloadImageRights" status="restricted">
                <licence>This image may be used in accord with fair use and fair dealing provisions, including teaching and research. If you wish to reproduce it within publications or on the public web, please make a reproduction request.</licence>
            </availability>
            <availability xml:id="metadataRights" status="restricted">
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This metadata is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International (CC BY-NC 4.0).</licence>
            </availability>

        </publicationStmt>

        <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
                <msIdentifier>
                    <repository>Cambridge University Library</repository>
                    <idno>MS Add. 8176: 127</idno>
                </msIdentifier>
                <msContents>
                    <msItem>
                        <title copyOf="#main_title"/>
                    </msItem>
                </msContents>
            </msDesc>
        </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
        <correspDesc>
            <correspAction type="sent">
                <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_31.xml">Lowe, R. T.</persName>
                <date when="1829-11-27">27 November 1829</date>
            </correspAction>
            <correspAction type="received">
                <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_1.xml">Henslow, J. S.</persName>
            </correspAction>
        </correspDesc>
        
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
        <change when="2014-06-06">Converted to XML by <name xml:id="hjones">Huw Jones</name>
         </change>
        <change when="2016-05-17">Converted to TEI P5 by <name xml:id="mjhawkins">Michael Hawkins</name>
         </change>
        <change when="2020-08-10" type="letter" status="released">Transcription cleared for online release</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
      <body>
        <div type="letter">
            <div type="text">
                <opener>
                    <placeName>Madeira</placeName>
                    <date>27 November 1829</date>
                    <salute>Dear Henslow</salute>
                </opener>
                <div type="transcription">
                     
                  <p>You will see by the date of the preceding page, how long I have been waiting for an opportunity to send this Prospectus. I must therefore beg the favour that you will as speedily as possible get it into print for me at Cambridge defraying the expences (I hope they will not be much) out of the Cam. Phil. Soc. money. It will print in small type well I sh <hi rend="superscript">d</hi> think on one 8. <hi rend="superscript">vo</hi> leaf w. <hi rend="superscript">ch</hi> will be far better than two. You will I am sure take the trouble to see that no mistakes are made: mind particularly or they will put an <hi rend="underline">i</hi> into Mad<hi rend="underline">e</hi>rensis. The number of copies I must leave entirely to y. <hi rend="superscript">r</hi> discretion. I sh. <hi rend="superscript">d</hi> wish about 20 or 30 to go to D <hi rend="superscript">r</hi>. Hooker; as many to Sowerby, &amp; 10 or a dozen to Miller of Bristol. I w. <hi rend="superscript">d</hi> not have <hi rend="underline">one</hi> sent to private friends, or put in private circulation. You will be the best judge for me in what periodicals to insert it, remembering how much I must study economy. The Quarterly I am afraid is very expensive or I sh. <hi rend="superscript">d </hi>like it much to have one. The Zoological, Brewster’s Journal &amp; the Botanical are essential. But perhaps D. <hi rend="superscript">r </hi>Hooker will be the best person to speak to about the two last. Put one or two for me if you please in the Philos. Soc. Reading room. All I wish to wish to avoid is <hi rend="underline">puffing, </hi>&amp;<hi rend="underline"> private </hi>puffing most of all.―</p>
                  <p>The first vessel direct to England will take a large box of birds directed to you for the Philos. Soc. from me. They are all I have been able to get together (you know I am no Ornithologist), but may be useful as authentic spec. <hi rend="superscript">ns</hi> I regret they have been set up, w.ch will make them very awkward to pack &amp; liable to injury <del>on the voyage</del>; but shall be wiser another time. They will possibly arrive in England the beginning of Jan <hi rend="superscript">y</hi>., &amp; as I know no better plan than directing them to the care of your brother, w. <hi rend="superscript">d</hi> it not be as well to tell him when to be looking out for them, that there may be no delay in the Docks.</p>
                  <p>Besides spending near 2 months in the North of the island, I have made the complete tour of it this Autumn, &amp; added greatly to my stores. This yr. remittance gave me the means to do; so that no time was lost in making what has really proved a good use of it. When you can ascertain what it may be necessary to deduct for printing this affair &amp;c I wish you would pay the remainder a bill of 25£12 <hi rend="superscript">s</hi>. I owe to Redfarn the Tailor. If you have not enough left for the whole, pay him part. This will save some trouble in remitting &amp;c― When Spring comes, I shall begin again, &amp; <del>take</del> make out my remaining 30£s worth in excursions, jars for Fish &amp;c. At the top of the box of Birds you will find a fine spec. <hi rend="superscript">n</hi> of Gorgonia verrucosa, with 2 or 3 Auriculae attached. Do with it what you please. It is quite at y. <hi rend="superscript">r</hi> service <del>If you</del> It w. <hi rend="superscript">d</hi> be desirable to send a few of the Prospectus to the Continent. Possibly you can do so without much trouble though some of y. <hi rend="superscript">r</hi> correspondents. <del>I think</del> I shall get Sowerby to send one to Ferussac.</p>
                  <p>I hope you have rec <hi rend="superscript">d.</hi> a parcel of Plants &amp;c. I sent you in July last by the Comet, directed to the care of y <hi rend="superscript">r.</hi> brother.―</p>
                  <p>Kind regards to all, particularly to L. Jenyns to whom I wrote some time since. | Y <hi rend="superscript">rs.</hi> sincerely | R. T. Lowe</p>
                  <p>Nov <hi rend="superscript">r.</hi> 30 <hi rend="superscript">th</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>The Packet has just arrived &amp; brought me a letter from L. Jenyns but no account from you of the Plants, Jar of fruit of Cycas &amp;c. I hope they are not lost. I have not yet been able to get you a SS <hi rend="superscript">n.</hi> of Palm or Dragon tree.―</p> 
                </div>
            </div>

        </div>
        
      </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
