<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="schema/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="HENSLOW-1098">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="main_title">To Thomas Martin 8 February 1854</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Henslow Correspondence Project</authority>
                <publisher>Henslow Correspondence Project</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
                <availability status="restricted">
                    <p>Available under license only</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="displayImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <p>Zooming image © Cambridge University Library, All rights reserved.</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="downloadImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <licence>This image may be used in accord with fair use and fair dealing
                        provisions, including teaching and research. If you wish to reproduce it
                        within publications or on the public web, please make a reproduction
                        request.</licence>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="metadataRights" status="restricted">
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This metadata is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International (CC BY-NC 4.0).</licence>
            </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>Bury St Edmunds Public Record Office</repository>
                        <collection/>
                        <idno>FL586/13/1: 13</idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <msItem>
                            <title copyOf="#main_title"/>
                        </msItem>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sent">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_1.xml">Henslow, J. S.</persName>
                    <date when="1854-02-08">8 February 1854</date>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="received">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_368.xml">Martin, Thomas</persName>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2014-06-06">Converted to XML by <name xml:id="hjones">Huw
                Jones</name>
         </change>
            <change when="2016-05-17">Converted to TEI P5 by <name xml:id="mjhawkins">Michael
                    Hawkins</name>
         </change>
        <change when="2020-08-10" type="letter" status="released">Transcription cleared for online release</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="letter">
                <div type="text">
                    <opener>
                        <placeName>Hitcham Hadley Suffolk</placeName>
                        <date>8 February 1854</date>
                        <salute>My dear Sir,</salute>
                    </opener>
                    <div type="transcription">
                        <p>I am much obliged by your last batch of notices – all useful in affording
                            hints, whether applicable to such a parish as this or not – we had been
                            doing something in the way of Rice – &amp; have had 1½ Tons to sell at
                            1d per lb. Besides 500 herrings, &amp; 1 lb of coarse sugar, to sweeten
                            the rice to the Children – I find the Rice has made great progress in
                            the affections of most of the people – Our plan was to allow such
                            families as had 2 or more children under 14 years, to purchase 10lb for
                            each child – &amp; those that had 3 or more to purchase (in
                            addition either 5lb of flour or 7lb more rice for 1d – the latter
                            receiving their quota in 2 deliveries (of which one will take place
                            tomorrow) – &amp; I find that more than half of those who preferred to
                            take the addition in flour last time now prefer to take all in rice – in
                            fact very few stick to the flour. On Tuesday I finish the course of 4
                            lectures I have been giving at Ipswich this winter, in reference to a
                            series of illustrations I am preparing for the Museum, &amp; I send you
                            a few newspaper strips of the notices of these illustrations, which have
                            already appeared – I have sketched out a plan for an epitome of Natural
                            History, in a series of typical objects (specimens, models &amp;
                            figures) which range on the floor of the Museum; &amp; from these
                            references one made to others in the cases round the room – [letter
                            cut] – notice I send you a copy I have retained for myself &amp; you
                            can return it – but possibly the enclosed [one may be?], to show you the
                            plan – My object is to make people (who visit a museum) think about,
                            &amp; not merely gape at the objects they see there – I have had rather
                            too many Irons in the fire for a man now 58, &amp; for the first time in
                            my life, my constitution has given me warning that I am getting old –
                            about 3 months ago a pain in my chest made my medical attendant
                            apprehensive that I might have some organic affections of the head; but
                            he &amp; Dr Billing (who examined me) now think it arose from dyspepsia
                            – I can now walk about freely again; instead of going to bed at 1, I get
                            there as soon after 10 as I can – live a little more freely – &amp;
                            clothe myself more warmly – I trust with a little less work than
                            heretofore I shall before long find myself re-established – indeed I
                            have only slight traces of the affections left – I accidentally saw Mr
                            [Sand?] in the train to Ipswich yesterday I was concerned to hear from him
                            that the son who was with you is seriously ill at home</p>
                        <p>Believe me</p>
                        <p>very truly yours</p>
                        <p>J. Henslow</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
