<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="schema/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="HENSLOW-1109">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="main_title">To Thomas Martin 10 February 1857</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Henslow Correspondence Project</authority>
                <publisher>Henslow Correspondence Project</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
                <availability status="restricted">
                    <p>Available under license only</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="displayImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <p>Zooming image © Cambridge University Library, All rights reserved.</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="downloadImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <licence>This image may be used in accord with fair use and fair dealing
                        provisions, including teaching and research. If you wish to reproduce it
                        within publications or on the public web, please make a reproduction
                        request.</licence>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="metadataRights" status="restricted">
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This metadata is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International (CC BY-NC 4.0).</licence>
            </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>Bury St Edmunds Public Record Office</repository>
                        <collection/>
                        <idno>FL586/13/1: 34</idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <msItem>
                            <title copyOf="#main_title"/>
                        </msItem>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sent">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_1.xml">Henslow, J. S.</persName>
                    <date when="1857-02-10">10 February 1857</date>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="received">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_368.xml">Martin, Thomas</persName>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2014-06-06">Converted to XML by <name xml:id="hjones">Huw
                Jones</name>
         </change>
            <change when="2016-05-17">Converted to TEI P5 by <name xml:id="mjhawkins">Michael
                    Hawkins</name>
         </change>
        <change when="2020-08-10" type="letter" status="released">Transcription cleared for online release</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="letter">
                <div type="text">
                    <opener>
                        <placeName>Hitcham, Bildeston, Suffolk</placeName>
                        <date>10 February 1857</date>
                        <salute>My dear Sir,</salute>
                    </opener>
                    <div type="transcription">
                        <p>It is very kind of you to offer me your aid – but I must decline it – I
                            am rather over-societed already, &amp; my pocket is not unfathomable as
                            regards expense, or my time sufficiently charged with leisure to allow
                            of my running up to town for a lecture at Soc. of Arts – I was at Dr
                            Royle’s lecture on E.I. fibres hoping to learn, rather than presuming to
                            teach on such a subject, &amp; I saw a new machine for extracting fibre
                            from the leaf of Plantains &amp; other Monocotyledons – Altho’ I
                            exhibited a large assortment of fibres &amp;c for a Country town – my
                            stock would have seemed comparatively insignificant besides by the side
                            of Dr Royle’s – If I lived in or near London I should belong to all such
                            societies but I have always resisted invitations to join the Athenaeum,
                            &amp; pay for an F. R. S. to my name – &amp; content myself with
                            Geological &amp; Linnean, as far as the Metropoles is concerned; &amp;
                            with the Phil. Soc. in Cambridge – This allows me to concentrate a little
                            more cash &amp; energy to our local institutions – &amp; especially to
                            the Museum at Ipswich of which I am president &amp; consequently bound
                            to do all I can in supporting its interests. What with two journeys to
                            visit paper mills, one in Surrey &amp; the other in Herts &amp; procuring
                            &amp; preparing specimens &amp; diagrams of my last lecture cost me in
                            money &amp; time rather more than I like to think of – I can assure you
                            it is from no desire to shun work that I decline your proposal – but I
                            am already taxed as far as prudence allows in respect of health, if
                            nothing else – I have to lecture at Bury on 10th March, &amp; to examine
                            at Cambridge during that month – so I have enough to think about at
                            present</p>
                        <p>We are sadly afflicted in the parish with a low typhus – &amp; I have
                            just returned from burying a stout hale man of 40 who died on Sunday,
                            leaving a widow &amp; 2 children dangerously ill – I hardly think that
                            one, a lad of 14, will recover, but the other, a nice little girl of
                            about 10, seems to have turned the corner after 3 or 4 weeks illness,
                            &amp; is smiling again – The widow was an old servant of ours, &amp; lost
                            2 children last winter from Measles &amp; Whooping Cough – Luckily her
                            eldest daughter is in Cambridge with her Grandfather, or she also would
                            now probably have taken the fever – It has been brought this year into
                            the parish from Stowmarket, as it was (without any doubt) last year from
                            Monk’s Eleigh – It is strange how completely it prostrates a family
                            &amp; lingers among them when it once gets hold of them</p>
                        <p>Believe me</p>
                        <p>very truly yours</p>
                        <p>J. S. Henslow</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
