<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="schema/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="HENSLOW-1104">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="main_title">To Thomas Martin 27 August 1855</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Henslow Correspondence Project</authority>
                <publisher>Henslow Correspondence Project</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
                <availability status="restricted">
                    <p>Available under license only</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="displayImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <p>Zooming image © Cambridge University Library, All rights reserved.</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="downloadImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <licence>This image may be used in accord with fair use and fair dealing
                        provisions, including teaching and research. If you wish to reproduce it
                        within publications or on the public web, please make a reproduction
                        request.</licence>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="metadataRights" status="restricted">
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This metadata is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International (CC BY-NC 4.0).</licence>
            </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>Bury St Edmunds Public Record Office</repository>
                        <collection/>
                        <idno>FL586/13/1: 32</idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <msItem>
                            <title copyOf="#main_title"/>
                        </msItem>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sent">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_1.xml">Henslow, J. S.</persName>
                    <date when="1855-08-27">27 August 1855</date>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="received">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_368.xml">Martin, Thomas</persName>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2014-06-06">Converted to XML by <name xml:id="hjones">Huw
                Jones</name>
         </change>
            <change when="2016-05-17">Converted to TEI P5 by <name xml:id="mjhawkins">Michael
                    Hawkins</name>
         </change>
        <change when="2020-08-10" type="letter" status="released">Transcription cleared for online release</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="letter">
                <div type="text">
                    <opener>
                        <placeName>Hitcham Hadleigh Suffolk</placeName>
                        <date>27 August 1855</date>
                        <salute>Dear Sir,</salute>
                    </opener>
                    <div type="transcription">
                        <p>I am very much obliged by your kind attention. The enclosed will need the
                            following explanations – The 3 sermons were finished under the idea that
                            they might direct attention a little more specially than on ordinary
                            occasions – &amp; perhaps reach some who never come to church. You must
                            not view them as laboured productions – the parish papers refer to my
                            method of carrying on such schemes rather by printed information than by
                            personal importunities, which I very greatly object to – to say nothing
                            of the loss of time incurred by running from house to house &amp;
                            feeling like “a busy-body”. The scraps from the Bury Post are a series
                            of letters in which I am still engaged (wanting No.1. of which I have no
                            copy &amp; which referred to our Farmers having had 17 ploughmen in the
                            field this year &amp; 20 of us dining together afterwards; a practice I
                            recommended to every village in Suffolk) – Those letters I intended for
                            purposes of agitation – to provoke a little preliminary enquiry into
                            matters referred to, before we come together next month to form a
                            Labourers Friend Socty. of which notice was given in the papers that it
                            was Sir Henry Bunbury’s intention to call us together – I am afraid that
                            the books named in my lending library list, are not all such as I wish
                            they were – but they were such as I happened to have – I have not sent
                            samples of tickets for Clubs on as you can easily understand what they
                            must be – Pray excuse this hurried note</p>
                        <p>Yrs very truly</p>
                        <p>J. S. Henslow</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
