<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="schema/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--OLD FILENAME:letters_306.xml-->
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="HENSLOW-306">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
            <title xml:id="main_title">From Charles Yate   10 November 1837</title>
        </titleStmt>
        <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Henslow Correspondence Project</authority>
            <publisher>Henslow Correspondence Project</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
            <availability status="restricted">
                <p>Available under license only</p>
            </availability>
            <availability xml:id="displayImageRights" status="restricted">
                <p>Zooming image © Cambridge University Library, All rights reserved.</p>
            </availability>
            <availability xml:id="downloadImageRights" status="restricted">
                <licence>This image may be used in accord with fair use and fair dealing provisions, including teaching and research. If you wish to reproduce it within publications or on the public web, please make a reproduction request.</licence>
            </availability>
            <availability xml:id="metadataRights" status="restricted">
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This metadata is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International (CC BY-NC 4.0).</licence>
            </availability>

        </publicationStmt>

        <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
                <msIdentifier>
                    <repository>Cambridge University Library</repository>
                    <idno>MS Add. 8177: 368</idno>
                </msIdentifier>
                <msContents>
                    <msItem>
                        <title copyOf="#main_title"/>
                    </msItem>
                </msContents>
            </msDesc>
        </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
        <correspDesc>
            <correspAction type="sent">
                <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_142.xml">Yate, Charles</persName>
                <date when="1837-11-10">10 November 1837</date>
            </correspAction>
            <correspAction type="received">
                <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_1.xml">Henslow, J. S.</persName>
            </correspAction>
        </correspDesc>
        
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
        <change when="2014-06-06">Converted to XML by <name xml:id="hjones">Huw Jones</name>
         </change>
        <change when="2016-05-17">Converted to TEI P5 by <name xml:id="mjhawkins">Michael Hawkins</name>
         </change>
        <change when="2020-08-10" type="letter" status="released">Transcription cleared for online release</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
      <body>
        <div type="letter">
            <div type="text">
                <opener>
                    <placeName>St John’s College</placeName>
                    <date>10 November 1837</date>
                    <salute>Dear Sir,</salute>
                </opener>
                <div type="transcription">
                     
                  <p>During my last summer’s ramble in Norway I had hoped to collect many plants, but owing to the rapidity of my movements, to say nothing of the difficulty of preserving &amp; carrying them, I was utterly unable. I send you however the few that I collected, tho’ I fear there is nothing worthy of your notice. The plant, which I take to be a Saxifrage, was very beautiful &amp; fragrant, when fresh gathered, &amp; was growing high up on the sunny side of a valley in the Dovre-Field chain of mountains. I only saw a few specimens in one spot, &amp; some of them were much larger than those I send; but their size prevented me from bringing them away.</p>
                    <p>I send also a few shells, which I gathered near Udevalla, in Sweden, from one of <hi rend="underline">the raised beaches</hi> described by M <hi rend="superscript">r</hi> Lyell. They are most abundant there, &amp; lie at an elevation at least 500 feet above the level of the sea, which is about a mile distant. It would seem that the whole peninsula of Norway &amp; Sweden has at some time been elevated; for a gentleman resident near Gothenburg in Sweden told me of similar beds in his neighbourhood. I heard of them also, from good authority, near Christiania, &amp; M <hi rend="superscript">r</hi> Laing, in his book on Norway, speaks of these beds being very abundant, north of Drontheim (sic), at a considerable elevation above the coast.</p>
                  <p>I fear that I shall appear to have taken useless trouble in forwarding these things to you, but if they sh. <hi rend="superscript">d </hi>be of the least value to you, it will be a satisfaction to</p>
                  <p>Your’s very faithfully | Charles Yate</p> 
                </div>
            </div>

        </div>
        
      </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
