<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="schema/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="HENSLOW-1105">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="main_title">To Thomas Martin 12 Oct 1855</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Henslow Correspondence Project</authority>
                <publisher>Henslow Correspondence Project</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
                <availability status="restricted">
                    <p>Available under license only</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="displayImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <p>Zooming image © Cambridge University Library, All rights reserved.</p>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="downloadImageRights" status="restricted">
                    <licence>This image may be used in accord with fair use and fair dealing
                        provisions, including teaching and research. If you wish to reproduce it
                        within publications or on the public web, please make a reproduction
                        request.</licence>
                </availability>
                <availability xml:id="metadataRights" status="restricted">
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This metadata is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International (CC BY-NC 4.0).</licence>
            </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>Bury St Edmunds Public Record Office</repository>
                        <collection/>
                        <idno>FL586/13/1: 37</idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <msItem>
                            <title copyOf="#main_title"/>
                        </msItem>
                    </msContents>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sent">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_1.xml">Henslow, J. S.</persName>
                    <date when="1855-10-12">12 Oct 1855</date>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="received">
                    <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_368.xml">Martin, Thomas</persName>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2014-06-06">Converted to XML by <name xml:id="hjones">Huw
                Jones</name>
         </change>
            <change when="2016-05-17">Converted to TEI P5 by <name xml:id="mjhawkins">Michael
                    Hawkins</name>
         </change>
        <change when="2020-08-10" type="letter" status="released">Transcription cleared for online release</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="letter">
                <div type="text">
                    <opener>
                        <placeName>tomorrow at Hitcham, Bildeston, Suffolk to stay at
                            Cambridge</placeName>
                        <date>12 Oct 1855</date>
                        <salute>My dear Sir,</salute>
                    </opener>
                    <div type="transcription">
                        <p>Leaving Hitcham for the Liverpool meeting of the British Association on
                            the day after our little Village fête – &amp; having back work to attend
                            to on my return, together with the fulfillment of an engagement to
                            assist with specimens &amp; voice at another Village Show a few miles
                            off, during the past week – &amp; now having come here to deposit my 2nd
                            son in his quarters at Christs Coll, I have been somewhat tardy in
                            acknowledging the receipt of pretty border to a Ticket of Merit you were
                            so good as to send me – I have unluckily ordered (before I got it)
                            something of the sort as I should have asked you whether I could not
                            purchase some of these – I think the pasteboard rather too thin – (the
                            specimen was crumpled &amp; spoilt for use) &amp; I rather fear the
                            colours wd fade in our smoky cottages– I mean to distribute more than
                            one annually for “superior allotment culture” – I have a neat plate
                            (wood cut) of a baptismal service with a certificate of baptism
                            appended, which finds its way into the cottages, &amp; some have several
                            on their walls– also a plate for our Playing match society – of which one
                            man has 5 on his walls – but the apathy of the farmers has allowed this
                            encouraging practice to fail for the last 2 years – tho’ I think it
                            likely it may revive with a little fresh blood lately imported – I think
                            you have seen these 2 plates – The proposed additions to them will, I
                            believe, be approved by the Labourers – it is no use asking for the
                            approbation of the Farmers who are mostly wonderfully apathetic (not to
                            say envious) about anything done to encourage their Labourers – but all
                            this you know well enough – Thanks for the Report which I will read as
                            soon as I get home &amp; see if I can’t gather a hint or two from
                            it</p>
                        <p>Believe me</p>
                        <p>very truly yours</p>
                        <p>J. S. Henslow</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
