<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="schema/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--OLD FILENAME:letters_918.xml-->
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="HENSLOW-918">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
            <title xml:id="main_title">From Lord Palmerston   30 May 1826</title>
        </titleStmt>
        <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Henslow Correspondence Project</authority>
            <publisher>Henslow Correspondence Project</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
            <availability status="restricted">
                <p>Available under license only</p>
            </availability>
            <availability xml:id="displayImageRights" status="restricted">
                <p>Zooming image © Cambridge University Library, All rights reserved.</p>
            </availability>
            <availability xml:id="downloadImageRights" status="restricted">
                <licence>This image may be used in accord with fair use and fair dealing provisions, including teaching and research. If you wish to reproduce it within publications or on the public web, please make a reproduction request.</licence>
            </availability>
            <availability xml:id="metadataRights" status="restricted">
               <licence target="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">This metadata is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International (CC BY-NC 4.0).</licence>
            </availability>

        </publicationStmt>

        <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
                <msIdentifier>
                    <repository>Cambridge University Library</repository>
                    <idno>MS Add. 8339:158</idno>
                </msIdentifier>
                <msContents>
                    <msItem>
                        <title copyOf="#main_title"/>
                    </msItem>
                </msContents>
            </msDesc>
        </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
        <correspDesc>
            <correspAction type="sent">
                <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_265.xml">Palmerston, Lord</persName>
                <date when="1826-05-30">30 May 1826</date>
            </correspAction>
            <correspAction type="received">
                <persName key="../nameregs/nameregs_1.xml">Henslow, J. S.</persName>
            </correspAction>
        </correspDesc>
        
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
        <change when="2014-06-06">Converted to XML by <name xml:id="hjones">Huw Jones</name>
         </change>
        <change when="2016-05-17">Converted to TEI P5 by <name xml:id="mjhawkins">Michael Hawkins</name>
         </change>
        <change when="2018-08-21" type="letter" status="released">File published</change>         
      </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
      <body>
        <div type="letter">
            <div type="text">
                <opener>
                    <placeName>Stan St.</placeName>
                    <date>30 May 1826</date>
                    <salute>My dear Sir</salute>
                </opener>
                <div type="transcription">
                     
                  <p>As I am sending to Waltham Cross about horses I take my chance of my servant being on time to put into the post this note with the inclosed which I have just received from our indefatigable Committee friend Flower Ellis of Trinity - I send you also todays report which is but scanty.</p>
                  <p>I have been told from pretty good authority that not very long ago Copleys promises were not much above 600, &amp; that he has had letters from a great many to say they cannot attend this of course is only for yourself. I shall send you down copies of the Summoning Circular, but I cannot send it off till Saturday, as it would not do to announce a Day of Election before the dissolution has actually taken place.</p>
                  <p>My dear Sir</p>
                  <p>Yrs sincerely</p>
                  <p>Palmerston</p>
                  <p>I have got two coaches for each day Tuesday Weddy &amp; Thursday. The Union for each of the days, the Wisbeach for Tuesday &amp; Thursday &amp; the Safety for Wednesday and I have ordered eight pair post horses at Waltham Cross, Ware Bunting Ford &amp; Royston for Monday Tuesday Weddy Thursday- we shall give at the Committee tickets by which our friends will gain admission into these Stages &amp; the use of the horses, our friends will settle with the Committee &amp; we shall thus secure the means of conveyance which might otherwise be wanting; I should suppose that very little arrangement will be necessary on the other roads though I hear that that Attorney Generals Commy have been at work about horses in the country but I doubt the necessity of our taking any measures. People will come from so many points that they will be sure to get to Cambridge and it is only our plumpers who would be impeded</p> 
                </div>
            </div>

        </div>
        
      </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
